highline.edu 2006-06-19

# Privacy Policy - Highline Community College

 Home > Privacy Policy

  * Introduction
  * Information collected and how it is used
  * Personal information and choice
  * Public access to information
  * Nondisclosure of certain personal information
    * Credit Card Payment
    * Degree Audit
    * Financial Aid Inquiry
    * Hope and Lifetime Learning Tax Credit
    * Registration
    * Registration Appointment
    * Schedule Planner
    * Student Address Change
    * Student PIN Change
    * Student Schedule
    * Unofficial Transcript
    * Library and Electronic Resources
    * Instructional Activities
  * Review and correction of personally identifiable information
  * Cookies
  * Security
  * Disclaimer
  * Highline Community College contact information

* * *

**Introduction**

Thank you for visiting the Highline Community College Web site and reviewing our Privacy Notice. This statement addresses collection, use, and security of and access to information that may be obtained through use of the Highline Community College Web site. This notice covers the following topics:

  * Information Collected and How it is Used 
  * Personal Information and Choice 
  * Public Access to Information 
  * Nondisclosure of Certain Personal Information 
  * Cookies 
  * Security 
  * Disclaimer
  * Contact Information 

This policy was approved June 18, 2002 by Highline Community College Executive Staff. 

Top of page

* * *

**Information Collected and How it is Used**

**Information collected if you only browse this site.**   
If you do nothing during your visit to our Web site but browse, read pages, or download information, we will gather and store certain information about your visit. This information does not identify you personally. We automatically collect and store the following information about your visit:

  1. The Internet Protocol Address and domain name used. The Internet Protocol address is a numerical identifier assigned either to your Internet service provider or directly to your computer. We use the Internet Protocol Address to direct Internet traffic to you. This address can be translated to determine the domain name of your service provider (for example, _xcompany.com_ or _yourschool.edu_ ); 
  2. The type of browser and operating system you used;
  3. The date and time you visited this site; 
  4. The Web pages or services you accessed at this site; and 
  5. The Web site you visited prior to coming to this Web site. 

The information we automatically collect or store is logged and used by Highline Community College only to improve the content of our Web services and to help us understand how people are using our services. Highline Community College analyzes the Web site logs to determine how our Web site is being used, so that we may continually improve the site's usefulness to the public.

**What we collect if you volunteer information.  
** If during your visit to our Web site you participate in a survey, send an e-mail, or perform some other transaction on-line, the following additional information will be collected:

  * The e-mail address, and contents of e-mail, for those who communicate with us via e-mail. 
  * Information volunteered in response to a survey. 
  * Information volunteered through an on-line form for any other purpose. 

The information collected is not limited to text characters and may include audio, video, and graphic information formats you send us.

We use your e-mail to respond appropriately. This may be to respond to you, to address issues you may identify, to further improve our Web site, or to forward the e-mail to another agency for appropriate action.

The use of survey information will be described as part of that survey. Information from other online forms is used for access to on-line student services, participation in instructional activities (such as on-line quizzes or on-line discussions), searches of library and other databases, and other activities as described in the specific application.

Top of page

* * *

**Personal Information and Choice**

You may choose whether to provide personal information online.

Personal information is information about a person that is readily identifiable to that specific individual. Personal information includes such things as an individual's name, address, and phone number. A domain name or Internet Protocol address is not considered personal information. 

We collect no personal information about you unless you voluntarily provide it to us by sending us e-mail, participating in a survey, or completing an on-line form. You may choose not to contact us by e-mail, participate in a survey or to provide any personal information using an online form. Your choice to not participate in these activities will not impair your ability to browse the Highline Community College Web site and read or download most information provided on the site.

Choosing not to participate in these activities may impair your ability to use on-line student services, participate in surveys, and participate in on-line instructional activities. On-line student services may be conducted using Touch-tone registration, mail, or telephone, as described in the section below on that specific service. Information about participating in surveys is available by contacting the office sponsoring the survey (identified on each individual survey), though some surveys will not be available off-line. Information about participating in instructional activities off-line is available by contacting the instructor, though some instructional activities may not be available off-line.

If personal information is requested on the Web site or volunteered by the user, state law and the federal Privacy Act of 1974 may protect it. However, this information is a public record once you provide it, and may be subject to public inspection and copying if not protected by federal or state law.

If you believe that your personal information is being used for a purpose other than what was intended when submitted, you may contact the Public Records Officer as shown in the Contact Information section of this statement.

Highline Community College web site is a general audience site and we do not knowingly collect any personal information from children. Users are cautioned that the collection of personal information requested from or volunteered by children online or by e-mail will be treated the same as information given by an adult, and may be subject to public access.

Top of page

* * *

**Public Access to Information**

In the State Of Washington, laws exist to ensure that government is open and that the public has a right to access appropriate records and information possessed by state government. At the same time, there are exceptions to the public's right to access public records that serve various needs including the privacy of individuals. Exceptions are provided by both state and federal laws. 

All of the information collected at this site becomes public records that may be subject to inspection and copying by members of the public, unless an exemption in law exists. Statue RCW 42.17. 260(1) states that: 

> Each agency, in accordance with published rules, shall make available for public inspection and copying all public records, unless the record falls within the specific exemptions of subsection (6) of this section [RCW 42.17.260(6)], RCW 42.17.310, 42.17.315, or other statute which exempts or prohibits disclosure of specific information or records. To the extent required to prevent an unreasonable invasion of personal privacy interests protected by RCW 42.17.310 and 42.17.315, an agency shall delete identifying details in a manner consistent with RCW 42.17.310 and 42.17.315 when it makes available or publishes any public record; however, in each case, the justification for the deletion shall be explained fully in writing.

In the event of a conflict between this Privacy Notice and the Public Records Act or other law governing the agency’s disclosure of records, the Public Records Act or other applicable law will control.

The complete Revised Code of Washington (RCW) is available at: [ http://wsl.leg.wa.gov/wsladm/rcw.cfm](http://wsl.leg.wa.gov/wsladm/rcw.cfm)

Top of page

* * *

**Nondisclosure of Certain Personal Information**

You may be required to provide certain personal information when you use the Web-enabled applications that are described below.

When using the applications, the following laws and regulations may prevent Highline Community College from disclosing the personal information about you except for directory information. Only directory information can be released without student's authorization. Students must sign a release in order to have any other information disclosed or to withhold all information. Education information may be released to other institutions that have requested the records and in which the student seeks or intends to enroll. Information may be released to a third party without student's consent if an emergency situation exists or if information is requested officially by means of a subpoena, court order or legal report. Additionally, Congress requires student information to be released to military recruiters if officially requested. Directory information may include student's name, address, telephone number, date and place of birth, major fields of study, participation in officially recognized activities and sports, weight and height of members of athletic teams, dates of attendance, degrees and awards received, the most recent previous educational agency or institution attended by the student, and other similar information.

  * Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 (FERPA)  
Section 438, Public Law 90-247 Title IV, as amended, 88 Stat 571-574 (20 USC 1232g) otherwise known as the Buckley Amendment Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act. 
  * [RCW 42.17.310](http://apps.leg.wa.gov/rcw/default.aspx) (a) exempts the following from public inspection and copying: (a) Personal information in any files maintained for students in public schools, patients or clients of public institutions or public health agencies, or welfare recipients; 

**Credit Card Payment**

Highline Community College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to pay tuition and fees over the Web. The information is required in order to verify your identity and to verify your credit card number and expiration date. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to apply tuition and fee payment over the Web, and you will have to pay your tuition and fees in person. Contact the Business Office at (206) 878-3710 ext. 3530 or [cashier@highline.edu](mailto:cashier@highline.edu) for more information.

In addition to the previously identified laws and regulations, the following applies:

  * [RCW 42.17.310 ](http://apps.leg.wa.gov/rcw/default.aspx)(ss) exempts the following from public inspection and copying: (ss) Credit card numbers, debit card numbers, electronic check numbers, card expiration dates, or bank or other financial account numbers supplied to an agency for the purpose of electronic transfer of funds, except when disclosure is expressly required by law. 

Top of page

**Degree Audit**

Highline Community College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to perform a degree audit of your records over the Web. The information is required in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to display a degree audit of your records over the Web, and you will have to request a degree audit in person. Contact Registration at (206) 878-3710 ext. 3243 or [registrar@highline.edu](mailto:registrar@highline.edu) for more information.

Top of page

**Financial Aid Inquiry**

Highline Community College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to obtain your financial aid status over the Web. The information is required in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to give you your financial aid status over the Web, and you will have to obtain this information in person. Contact Financial Aid at (206) 878-3710 ext. 3358 or [financialaid@highline.edu](mailto:financialaid@highline.edu) for more information.

Top of page

**Hope and Lifetime Learning Tax Credit**

Highline Community College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to allow you to view and copy course enrollment and payment information. The information is required in order to provide you with the tax information needed for compliance with the Internal Revenue Service reporting requirements for the Hope and Lifetime Learning tax credits. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it, we will be unable to display your enrollment and payment information and you will have to obtain a copy of your enrollment and payment records in person. Contact the Cashier at (206) 878-3710 ext. 3320 or [cashier@highline.edu](mailto:cashier@highline.edu) for more information.

Top of page

**Registration**

Highline Community College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to register for classes over the Web. The information is required in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it you will be unable to register for classes over the Web, and you will have to register for classes in person. Contact Registration at (206) 878-3710 ext. 3243 or [registrar@highline.edu](mailto:registrar@highline.edu) for more information.

Top of page

**Registration Appointment**

Highline Community College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to obtain your registration appointment information over the Web. The information is required in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to display your registration appointment information over the Web, and you will have to obtain your registration appointment information address in person. Contact Registration at (206) 878-3710 ext. 3243 or [ registrar@highline.edu](mailto:registrar@highline.edu) for more information. 

Top of page

**Schedule Planner**

Highline Community College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to check requisites while using schedule planner. The information is required in order to access your academic and testing records. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to verify your eligibility for enrollment into certain classes and you may be blocked from enrolling into those classes. Contact Registration at (206) 878-3710 ext. 3243 or [registrar@highline.edu](mailto:registrar@highline.edu) for more information.

Top of page

**Student Address Change**

Highline Community College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to change your address over the Web. The information is required in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to change your address over the Web, and you will have to change your address in person. Contact Registration at (206) 878-3710 ext. 3243 or [registrar@highline.edu](mailto:registrar@highline.edu) for more information.

Top of page

**Student PIN Change**

Highline Community College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to change your personal identification number over the Web. The information is required in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to change your PIN over the Web, and you will have to change your PIN in person. Contact Registration at (206) 878-3710 ext. 3243 or [ registrar@highline.edu](mailto:registrar@highline.edu) for more information.

Top of page

**Student Schedule**

Highline Community College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to view your quarterly schedule. The information is required in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to display your quarterly schedule over the Web, and you will have to obtain a copy of your quarterly schedule in person. Contact Registration at (206) 878-3710 ext. 3243 or [ registrar@highline.edu](mailto:registrar@highline.edu) for more information.

Top of page

**Unofficial Transcript**

Highline Community College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to view your unofficial transcript over the Web. The information is required in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to display your unofficial transcript over the Web, and you will have to view your unofficial transcript in person. Contact Registration at (206) 878-3710 ext. 3243 or [registrar@highline.edu](mailto:registrar@highline.edu) for more information.

Top of page

**Library, Electronic Resources, and Instructional Computing Resources**

Highline Community College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to access and use certain resources in the library, and to use computers on campus. The information is required in order to conduct business of the library and college, such as tracking overdue materials or managing the efficient functioning of the workstation or network. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to provide certain library, computing, and information resource services to you. Contact the Dean of Instructional Resources, at (206) 878-3710 ext. 3230 for more information.

In addition to the previously identified laws and regulations, the following apply:

  * [RCW 42.17.310](http://apps.leg.wa.gov/rcw/default.aspx) (l) exempts the following from public inspection and copying: (l) Any library record, the primary purpose of which is to maintain control of library materials, or to gain access to information, which discloses or could be used to disclose the identity of a library user. 
    * For the purposes of this regulation, Highline’s workstation and network logs that collect and retain information concerning information resources accessed shall be considered library records.
  * Highline Community College Library [ Policy on the Privacy of Library Records](http://flightline.highline.edu/libraryadmin/a_policies/privacy.html).
  * 50 U.S.C. 1861 et seq.. Under the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act, ("FISA"), the FBI may obtain an ex parte (without a formal hearing) court order allowing access to the records of library patrons.

Top of page

**Instructional Activities**

Highline Community College may require you to provide certain personal information as part of instructional activities which occur on-line or over the Web. In such cases, the information is required as part of participation in the class. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it you will be unable to participate in those aspects of the class which occur on the Web. Contact your instructor or the Vice President for Academic Affairs at (206) 870-3711.

Top of page

* * *

**Review and Correction of Personally Identifiable Information**

You can review any personally identifiable information that Highline Community College collects about you by using the information in the Contact Information section at the end of this Notice. You may recommend changes to your personally identifiable information you believe to be inaccurate by submitting a written request that credibly shows the inaccuracy. We will take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access or making corrections ([RCW 43.105.310](http://apps.leg.wa.gov/rcw/default.aspx)).

Top of page

* * *

**Cookies**

To better serve our users, we may use "cookies" to customize your browsing experience with Highline Community College. Cookies are simple text files stored on your computer by your Web browser.

Cookies created on your computer by using this Web site may contain limited personally identifying information, and will not compromise your privacy or security. We may use the cookie feature to store session login information or limited personal information, such as your name.

Top of page

* * *

**Security**

Highline Community College, as developer and manager of the Highline Community College Web site, has taken several steps to safeguard the integrity of its data and prevent unauthorized access to information maintained by Highline Community College. These measures are designed and intended to prevent corruption of data, block unknown or unauthorized access to our systems and information, and to provide reasonable protection of private information in our possession.

This information should not be construed in any way as giving business, legal, or other advice, or warranting as fail proof, the security of information provided via Highline Community College's Web sites.

Top of page

* * *

**Disclaimer**

The Highline Community College Web site has many links to other Web sites. These include links to Web sites operated by other government agencies, nonprofit organizations and private businesses. When you link to another site, you are no longer on the Highline Community College Web site and this Privacy Notice will not apply. When you link to another Web site, you are subject to the privacy policy of that new site.

Neither the State of Washington, nor any agency, officer, or employee of the State of Washington warrants the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of any information published by this system, nor endorses any content, viewpoints, products, or services linked from this system, and shall not be held liable for any losses caused by reliance on the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of such information. Portions of such information may be incorrect or not current. Any person or entity that relies on any information obtained from this system does so at their own risk.

Highline Community College reserves the right to revise and update this Privacy Notice at any time by posting such revised Privacy Notice at the Highline Community College home page.

Top of page

* * *

**Highline Community College Contact Information**  

You may contact Highline Community College as follows:

To review your personal information, or request correction of your personal information:

> Public Records Officer  
>  Highline Community College  
>  M/S 6-11  
>  2400 S. 240th Street  
>  Des Moines, WA 98198  
> (206)-878-3710 ext. 3559  
> Fax: (206)-870-3780   

To offer comments about Highline Community College's Web site or about the information presented in this Privacy Notice:

> Public Web Site Coordinator  
>  Highline Community College  
>  2400 S. 240th Street  
>  Des Moines, WA 98198  
> (206)-878-3710 ext. 6106  
>  Fax: (206)-870-3744
